T Ravi Kumar

Senior Software Engineer

9.9 years of experience in Mule Soft and Java. Have an expertise in designing and developing of Applications using RAML. Spring Boot, Spring MVC and RESTful Web Services. I'm always eager for exploring other technologies.

- Having 2.6 years of Design, development and maintenance experience in MuleSoft.
- Having 7.3 years of Design, development and maintenance experience in Java.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer Volvo

03/2018 - Present & 3.7 Yrs.

Bangalore, KA, India

- Tech Stack: - MuleSoft , Java 8, RAML, Data Weave, Oracle, JMS,RestFul,SpringBoot,Spring,Hibernate,Postgres, Mongo DB ,Maven, Jenkin , AWS (EC2,S3),PostMan,JIRA,PG Admin,Log4j2

Senior Software Engineer CenturyLink

08/2016- 01/2018 & 1.5 Yrs.

Bengaluru, KA, India

- Tech Stack: - Spring MVC, RestFul , Java 7 , Hibernate, Oracle ,Maven , Jenkin , JSP, Junit, HP QC,PL/SQL Developer.

Software Engineer **CapGemini**

01/2012 - 08/2016 & 4.7 Yrs.

Bengaluru, KA, India

- Tech Stack: - Spring MVC, Restful , Java 7 , Hibernate, Log4j, JavaScript, Oracle, Maven, SVN, CVS, Rally.

EDUCATION

MCA

SVPCET, JNTU, Puttur

08/2007 - 06/2010,

74%

PROFESSIONAL RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Hands on experience in Design, Developing Implementation of applications using MuleSoft.
- Develop mule ESB projects for the services with synchronous and Asynchronous mule flows
- Strong Experience in creating Flows, Sub Flows, Private flows and used Data Weave extensively for transformations in Mule Anypoint studio
- Experience in Design and Implementing RAML Specification using Anypoint platform
- Designed and developed Mule ESB projects using various components like FTP, HTTP, Scatter-Gather, Validation, Database, Choice-Router, Batch Process, Cache etc.
- Designing and implementing the error handling in MuleSoft
- Handling all the Prod Release related Activities [Team Lead Activities].
- Following SCRUM Software Development Life Cycle with PI.
- Working on Prod issues related Tickets.
- Worked on Code migration from Legacy to Microservices.
- Created Component and Integration Tests Using Mokito &
- Worked on Tomcat 8, Jboss Wildfly 8.X servers for deploying Applications.

SKILLS



Mobile No: 8792794045

Email: ravithirumala25@gmail.com

PROJECTS

VGT Telematics (03/2018 - Present)

VGT Telematics is used for Tracking, Tracing and Monitoring the vehicles and drivers.

Modules:

Track.Trace.Vehicle Reports, Driver Reports, Fuel Loss Alerts and Reports, Geofence Alerts, Service Conversion, Open API, Driver Creation. Vehicle Creation and Auto Activation.

DOCS (08/2016 - 01/2018)

DOCS (Distributed On-Line Correspondence System) is a workflow management application that is used in the Offline centers to receive. manage and process a variety of work requests. Modules:

Task Management, Reports Management, User Management, Profile Management, Group Management, Category Management, Email Management, Web Forms

MyGEAviation - Materials (01/2012 - 08/2016)

It is a GE initiative that has been established to grow the GE Aviation services offerings to Airline Customers. This effort is seeking to leverage new and emerging technologies in union with the comprehensive information about engines to offer the customer a more robust, portable, and satisfying level of access to vital information across the life of the engines. my Engines is intended to be a Tool for customers to communicate with GE and monitor engines through simple, relevant, real-time updates, customized by user interest.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- I have successfully completed OCJP Certification.
- I got Pat on the back award from Capgemini.
- I got Spot award from Century link.
- I was a cricket team caption in CenturyLink Cricket Tournament.

OTHERS TECHINICAL SKILLS

- Having Knowledge on MDW Workflow.
- Having good knowledge on OSGI and Fuse ESB. Having knowledge on SIF call integration for informatica siperian mdm hub.
- Having knowledge on Apache Hadoop Framework and Ecosystem like HDFS, MapReduce, Hive, Pig, Sqoop, HBase.